(月詠)もっと… 早くに
話をしてほしかった｡
I wish you had told me this sooner.
わっちにも 遠慮なく
その荷 分けてほしかった｡
I wish you had allowed me
to share your burden.
弟子を荷ごと背負うのが
師匠の役目なら➡
If the master's duty is to shoulder
the student along with their pain,
弟子の役目は なんじゃ？
what is the student's duty?
師を背負えるまでに
大きくなることじゃ｡
To grow strong enough
to shoulder the master.
軽い… 軽いのう 師匠｡
You're light...
So light, Master...
ぬしは こんなにも
軽かったんじゃな｡
I never knew you were so light...
見えるか？ 師匠｡
Can you see, Master?
(地雷亜)ああ… 見える｡
Yes...
I can see...
今まで見たことがないほどの➡
A moon more beautiful...
きれいな月だ…｡
than any... I've ever seen...
(全蔵)大した弟子だな｡
That's one helluva student.
師匠を背負えるまで
大きくなるのが 弟子の務めか｡
A student's duty is to grow strong enough
to shoulder the master, huh?
ｵﾚは 親父には背負われてばかりで
そんなﾏﾈしてやれなんだな｡
I was always relying on my old man,
so I was never able to do that.
(銀時)ｵﾚもだ｡
...Same here.
(新八)だいぶ
復興が進んできましたね｡
Reconstruction is coming
along smoothly.
いや～ よかった よかった｡
Boy, that's a relief.
この分じゃ そうかからず
元の吉原に戻りそうだ｡
At this rate, Yoshiwara will be
back to the way it was in no time.
(日輪)みんなの協力のおかげだよ｡
We were able to keep the
damage to a minimum.
被害を
最小限に食い止められたのも➡
奇跡的に 死者を
ひとりも出さなかったのも｡
And miraculously, there
were no casualties.
ああ あの忍者さんに
お礼を言わなきゃね｡
Oh, I need to thank that ninja, too.
また来るかしら？
Will he be coming by again?
He's probably drinking at some
cabaret full of fuglies.
そこらへんのﾌﾞｽ専ｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗで
飲んでんじゃね？
それにしても 月詠さんの様子は
どうなんですか？ あれから｡
In any case, how has Tsukuyo-san
been doing?
傷は癒えたんだけど…
心の傷のほうがね｡
She's recovered from
her physical injuries,
but her emotional scars, well...
あれから 部屋で
ふさぎこんでるの｡
She's been in her room
since the incident.
(日輪)ﾑﾘもないわ｡
Who can blame her?
She went through so much.
あれだけ
いろいろなことがあったんだし➡
And she also feels responsible.
それに責任を感じてるみたい｡
自分のせいで
こんな事態になってしまったって｡
She believes it's her fault
that this happened.
(神楽)ﾂｯｷｰのせいじゃないのに…｡
But it isn't Tsukky's fault.
ちょっと行って
慰めてくるｱﾙか？
Should we go cheer her up?
ほっとけ ほっとけ｡
今まで働きづめだったんだ｡
Just leave her alone.
She's been working nonstop
this whole time.
たまには さぼりてぇんだろ｡
Probably feels like taking
a break for a change.
That's true...
そうですね… あっ そうだ！
Oh, that's it!
せっかく休みなんだし➡
Since she's taking a break,
月詠さん 外に遊びに
連れ出してあげましょうよ｡
we should take her out.
いい気分転換になると思うし｡
It'll be a good change of pace.
何 面倒くさいこと
提案してんの お前｡
Why are you coming up with ideas
that mean more work for us?
ｲﾔだよ ｵﾚ｡
これから ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺ行くんだから｡
I won't do it.
I'm gonna hit the pachinko parlor.
いい案ね！ お願い｡
That's a wonderful idea.
Please.
あの娘 働きづめで
ﾛｸに地上に出たこともないの｡
She was always working so she's
never been to the surface.
ｽｶｯ とするところに
案内してあげて｡
Introduce her to a place
where she can relax.
ねぇ 日輪さん｡
人の話 聞いてる？
Say, Hinowa-san...
Weren't you listening to me?
ｱﾝﾀさ さり気に人使い 荒いよね？
You're pretty abusive, huh?
結構 ｸﾞｲｸﾞｲ頼みごとしてくるよね？
Rattling off request after request.
月詠ちゃ～ん！ 遊ぼ!!
Tsukuyo-chan!
Let's go play!
おい 起きろ こら｡
ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺ行くぞ｡
Hey, wake up, damn it.
We're hitting the pachinko parlor.
ｵﾒｴ 結構 貯めこんでんだろ？
全部 ﾊﾟ～ｯと使ってやっからよ｡
You probably got a bunch
saved up, right?
I'll blow it all for you.
あれ？ いないのかな｡
Huh? She isn't here?
もういいだろう｡ ほっとけ｡
Forget it. Just leave her alone.
ｵﾚは もう行くぜ！
I'm leaving.
今日は なんだか
出そうな気がするんだい｡
I feel like I'm gonna hit
something big today.
...Jackpot?
ｹﾞｷｱﾂ！
なにさらしとんじゃ～!!
The hell are you doing?!
["Watch Out For A Set of Women and A Drink"]
そうか… わっちが
あの一件で沈んでいるものと…｡
I see...
You all thought I was feeling
down from the incident.
いろいろ 気を遣わせて
しまったようじゃな｡
Looks like I made everyone worry.
すまぬ 余計な心配ばかりかけて｡
Sorry to cause unnecessary concern.
だが このとおり
わっちは元気じゃ｡
But as you can see, I'm fine.
心配いらんぞ｡
You don't need to worry.
いやぁ ﾎﾝﾄ
ありあまってるみたいだね 元気｡
Yeah, no kidding.
Too fine, if you ask me.
ﾎﾝﾄ なによりだわ！
それが なによりだわ｡
Great to hear.
Really, that's great to hear.
あの…
部屋から出てこないくらい➡
Uh, we heard that you were too
depressed to leave your room.
落ち込んでるって
聞いたんですけど…｡
うむ 少々 傷を負っていたのでな｡
Yes, I was somewhat injured.
これで働くと言えば
日輪がうるさい｡
Hinowa would give me an
earful if I went out to work.
芝居をうって
部屋で寝ているﾌﾘをして➡
I did a little acting and
pretended to sleep,
抜け穴から外に出ていたのだ｡
before sneaking outside
through a side exit.
えっ!? あんなことがあったあとも
働いてたんですか？ あんな体で!?
Huh?
You were still working after that?!
In that condition?!
当たり前じゃ｡
Of course.
吉原が これだけ
打撃を受けたというのに➡
Yoshiwara has taken a big hit.
ｹｶﾞぐらいで休んでいられるか｡
I can't be resting, just
because I'm injured.
それに違法薬物は
影をひそめたとはいえ➡
Besides, even if the illegal
drugs have disappeared,
まだまだ吉原の治安は悪い｡
crime is still a problem in Yoshiwara.
寝ている暇も 落ち込んでいる暇も
わっちにはないわ｡
I don't have time to sleep
or be depressed.
まあ そのせいで日輪たちには➡
Well, I made Hinowa and the
others worry unnecessarily.
いらぬ心配を
かけてしまったようじゃ｡
傷も癒えたことだし そろそろ
大手を振って働きに出て➡
I've recovered from my injuries.
I should start working in the open
元気な姿でも見せるとしよう｡
and show them that I'm doing fine.
ということじゃ｡
There you have it.
Sorry to cause you trouble,
気を遣ってもらって
悪いんじゃが➡
わっちには
ﾘﾌﾚｯｼｭ休暇など必要ありんせん｡
but I don't need a vacation to rejuvenate.
わっちは もう大丈夫じゃ｡
いろいろ ありがとうな｡
I'm fine now.
Thank you for everything.
忙しくて今はﾑﾘじゃが➡
I'm too busy right now,
ぬしらには
いずれ改めて礼をさせてもらう｡
but at some point, I'd like
to properly thank you.
わっちは 構ってやれぬが
ゆっくりしていってくれ｡
I can't provide much service,
but enjoy your stay.
月詠さん
なんにも変わりませんね｡
Tsukuyo-san hasn't changed.
(日輪)ﾎﾝﾄに あいかわらず➡
She's still the same.
弱みをなかなか
人に見せないﾔﾂだよ｡
Never letting anyone else
see her weak side.
つくづく不器用な娘だね｡
She just doesn't know how to open up.
あんなことがあったから
少しは変わると思ったのに➡
I thought she would have changed
after everything that happened.
人間そうそう
変わらないものｱﾙな｡
I guess people can't change so easily.
本当に苦しいときは
言ってくれるさ｡
She'll let us know when
she's really suffering.
ﾔﾂは 人より それを
ｷﾞﾘｷﾞﾘまでしないﾔﾂなんだよ｡
She just puts that off considerably
more than the average person.
んなこと言ったって 銀さん｡
But Gin-san...
That just means she's pushing
herself too hard.
要するに
ﾑﾘしてるってことでしょ｡
ほっとけ｡
Leave her alone.
There isn't anything for us to do.
ｵﾚたちにできることは
もう何もねえよ｡
はぁ… 少しは 息抜きさせて
あげたかったんだけどね｡
I wanted to let her take a break.
働いてるほうがいいってんなら
しかたないかね｡
Guess that won't happen
if she would rather work.
(晴太)でも あんな
ﾑﾘばっかりしてたら➡
But she'll ruin her health if she
keeps pushing herself like that!
いつか壊れちゃうよ 月詠ねえ｡
休むのがｲﾔなら
働きながらﾘﾌﾚｯｼｭすればいい話ね｡
If she won't take a break, we just have
to help her rejuvenate on the job.
そんな いい方法があったら
苦労しないよ｡
There wouldn't be any problem
if it was that easy.
遊びながら お酒でも飲みながら
働こうってわけ？
Are you telling her to play around
or drink while working?
そんな仕事…｡
What kind of job...
Oh...!
いらっしゃいませ！
Welcome, savior of Yoshiwara!
吉原の救世主様！
よう来てくれはりました｡
さあ さあ こちらへ｡
Thank you for coming.
Now, come this way.
あの… ﾀﾀﾞ酒飲ませてくれるって
いうから来たけどﾏｼﾞなの？
Um...
I came because I was told there'd
be free drinks, but is that for real?
ｵﾚ 金ないよ｡ ﾊﾟﾁﾝｺ負けたし｡
I'm flat-out broke.
Since I lost at pachinko.
ええ｡ ﾏｼﾞでございます｡
Yes, it's our way of saying thanks.
銀様には今まで何度も
吉原を救ってもらったんですもの｡
You've saved Yoshiwara so many times.
今夜は思う存分
遊んでいってくださいましね｡
Please enjoy yourself tonight.
おいおい ﾏｼﾞでか？
ﾀﾀﾞ酒どころか あれか｡
Whoa, is this for real?!
Are you saying I can have free drinks,
ﾜｶﾒ酒とかも
やっていいわけ？ それって｡
AND also try some seaweed sake?
もう ﾜｶﾒどころか
ｱﾜﾋﾞの踊り食いから 栗拾いまで➡
Oh, don't just stop at seaweed, sir.
Anything from dancing clams
to picking chestnuts.
何でもありですよ｡
ちょ待てよお前 栗拾いはﾏｽﾞｲだろ｡
ﾓﾝﾌﾞﾗﾝとか作っちゃうよｵﾚ｡
Hold it! You shouldn't get nuts involved!
I'll end up with a Mont Blanc, you know?!
栗ご飯とかも
炊いちゃうよｵﾚ いいの？
Cook myself some rice with nuts!
Is that really okay?!
構いませんよ！
存分に楽しんでいってください！
That's fine!
Enjoy yourself all you want.
すみません｡ 何か困ったことが
あったら またいつでも呼んで｡
You know, call me if you ever
need any help again.
いつでも飛んで来るからｵﾚ｡
いつでも栗ご飯炊くから｡
I'll come flying at a moment's notice.
I'll cook nut rice at a moment's notice.
いや～ 新八と神楽
連れてこないでﾎﾝﾄよかったわ｡
Yeah, it's a good thing I didn't
bring Shinpachi and Kagura.
こちらの座敷でございます｡
You'll be in this room.
では ごゆっくりと｡
Then please enjoy yourselves.
い… いらっしゃいませ｡
あ どうもどうも｡
W-Welcome.
Ah, hello there.
死神太夫 月詠でありんす｡
どうぞ よしな…｡
I am the Courtesan of Death, Tsukuyo.
Please enjoy your...
死神太夫 月詠でありんす｡
どうぞ よしな…｡
I am the Courtesan of Death, Tsukuyo.
Please enjoy your...
Change!
ﾁｪﾝｼﾞ！ ﾁｪﾝｼﾞお願いします！
Change please!
もっと愛想がいい娘に！
Get me a girl who's more friendly!!
おい これはどういうことじゃ｡
Hey, what's the meaning of this?
何で ぬしがこんなところにおる｡
Why are you here?
そりゃｺｯﾁのｾﾘﾌだ！
何でお前が 聞いてねえぞ！
That's my line!
Why are you...!
Nobody mentioned this!
こんな無愛想な女に
酌してもらっても➡
Any drink will taste bad when served
by such a grumpy woman.
何も うまくねえっつうの！
大事な仕事だと 日輪に頼まれた｡
Hinowa requested me to perform
this important job.
大層な上客が来ると｡
She said that an important customer
would be coming.
((他の女の子たちは みんな
吉原の復旧で 手がまわらないの｡
The other girls are busy with Yoshiwara's
reconstruction so they can't help.
お願い 月詠｡ お酌だけでも
いいからしてきてもらえる？))
Please, Tsukuyo.
Could you at least pour a drink for him?
これも立派な仕事のひとつだと｡
I was told that this was an important job.
ｱｲﾂら ﾊﾒやがったな｡
T-those bastards got me good...
ｵﾚに ｻｰﾋﾞｽするどころか➡
So much for providing me service...
結局 ｺｲﾂのﾘﾌﾚｯｼｭに
かりだされたってわけかよ｡
They were just using me to
help rejuvenate this woman.
It looks like Gin-san's figured
out what's going on.
銀さん
感づいちゃったみたいですよ｡
ごめんなさい 銀さん｡
I'm sorry, Gin-san.
月詠は休めって言って
休む娘じゃないの｡
Tsukuyo isn't the type of girl
to rest during her time off.
仕事って名目で
ﾊﾒ外させるしかないのよ｡
I have to use the pretense of a
job to allow her to take it easy.
どうか
その娘の気を晴らさせてあげて｡
Please help her relax.
銀さんなら きっとできるから｡
I'm sure that Gin-san can do it.
よくわからんが
日輪が言いたかったのは➡
I can't be sure,
but I assume that Hinowa was
trying to say that serving you,
吉原を何度も救ってくれた
ぬしをもてなすのも➡
someone who's saved Yoshiwara
many times,
立派な仕事のひとつ
ということなのだろう｡
was also an important job.
吉原の女たちを代表して
わっちが ぬしに礼をしろと｡
That I represent the women of
Yoshiwara in thanking you.
いや 多分そういう
かたいのじゃないと思う｡
No, I'm pretty sure it's
nothing that formal.
まあ いい｡ ぬしには どのみち
礼をせねばならんかったのじゃ｡
No matter, I also wanted
to show my appreciation.
これで 気が済むんじゃろう？
ｵﾚは悪代官か!?
Is this good enough?
Do I look like a corrupt politician to you?!
どんな礼のしかたを
しようとしてんだ！
What kind of appreciation is that?!
Hinowa would never tell you to do that!
日輪が そんなこと
させるわけ ねえだろ！
でも 酌だけでもしてこい と｡
But she told me to provide service.
Not THAT kind of service!
しゃくって
そっちのしゃくじゃねえよ！
For someone so pure, you
sure know your stuff!
お前 おぼこっぽく見えて
意外に詳しいのな！
You really are a woman of Yoshiwara!
さすがは 吉原の女な！
では 何をすればよいのじゃ？
What am I supposed to do then?
座敷になど
あがったことはないから➡
I've never been in one
of these rooms before.
何も わからん｡
しかたねえな…｡
Guess I don't have a choice.
とりあえず 飲め｡
For now, just drink.
いろいろあったが 今日は
よけいなことを 全部忘れて 飲め｡
A lot's happened,
but for today, just forget it all and drink.
それが 今日のお前の仕事だ｡
That's your job today.
ﾌﾌﾌ… さすがは 銀さん
わかってくれた｡
That's our Gin-san.
He knows what to do.
あぁ 飲んだ！ 母ちゃん！
月詠ねえ お酒 飲んだよ｡
Oh, she drank.
Mom, she drank.
(日輪)よかった…
それでいいのよ 月詠｡
That's wonderful. This is how
it should be, Tsukuyo.
いけるｸﾁじゃねえか｡
You can hold your liquor, huh?
(日輪)ああしてると
本当に 普通の女の子みたい｡
She looks like a normal girl now.
たまには こうして ﾊﾒを外して
ゆっくり休めばいいのよ 月詠｡
You should relax and rest every
once in a while, Tsukuyo.
ﾋｯｸ！
Hey, don't drink it all. Pour me some.
おい！ ﾃﾒｴばっか飲んでねえで
ｵﾚにも酌しろよ｡
ったく…
どっちが客か わかりゃしねえな｡
Man, who's serving who here?
ﾋｯｸ！
あ？
Huh?
ﾋｯｸ！ 注げ｡
Pour.
Pour!
えっ!?
Huh?!
酒が足んねえっつってんだ！
えぇ～っ!?
I said there ain't enough liquor!
樽ごと持ってこんかい わりゃ！
Bring the whole damn barrel!
え… えぇ～っ!?
Wha-
だ… だ だ… 誰!? あれ！
ﾋｯｸ！
W-who the hell is THAT?!
She's turned into a completely different
person after one shot?!
お酒１杯で 別人に
豹変しちゃったんですけど！
She's not just cutting loose anymore!
ﾊﾒ 外すっていうか
なんか 別の大切なものが➡
Something more important just got loose!
外れちゃったみたいなんですけど｡
おい ｺﾗ！ いつまで寝てんだよ!!
Hey, damn it!
How long you gonna lie there?!
ちょっと！ 全然
普通の女の子じゃないよ あれ!!
Hold it, hold it!!
That definitely isn't a normal girl!
She's acting like a drunk old man!
何!? あれ！
立ち飲み屋のおっさんだよね!!
Gin-chan!
(神楽)銀ちゃん！
銀ちゃんが殺される!!
She's gonna kill Gin-chan!
Hey, wake up.
おい 起きろ！
早々と潰れてんじゃないよ｡
It's too early to get smashed.
夜は まだまだ これからだろ｡
The night's only begun.
あ… す… すみません！
Yeah, s-sorry...
ちょっと 急に意識が…｡
飲みすぎちゃったかな？
I suddenly lost consciousness.
Maybe I drank too much.
お お… おかしいな？ もう
帰ったほうがいい… いい… かも｡
Th-That's odd.
Maybe I should l-l-leave.
あぁ!?
ﾃﾒｴ 私の敷居 またいどいて➡
You come to my house and think that
you can leave before the sun rises?
日が昇る前に
帰れると思ってんのか!?
冗談ですよ！
勘弁してくださいよ 月詠太夫｡
I'm joking. Please forgive
me, Lady Tsukuyo.
朝まで お供しますってば！
I'll accompany you till morning.
I'll kill all the morning birds and
accompany you till morning,
三千世界の鴉をぶち殺して
朝までお供しますってば！
つうか 太夫… ｵﾚ いつから
太夫と飲んでましたっけ？
But um, Lady...
When did we start drinking together?
途中で ﾁｪﾝｼﾞとかしましたっけ？
Was there a change at some point?
最初から太夫ですよね？
太夫が太夫ですよね？
I was with the Lady to begin with?
You're the Lady, right?
Obviously!
あたりめえだろ！
今日は ｵﾒｴのために➡
I dressed up and prepared
all this liquor for you today!
こうして おめかしして 酒まで
用意して 待ってたんだろうが！
殺すぞ この野郎！
I'm gonna kill you, bastard!
し… 知らなかった｡ あの娘が
あんなにお酒が弱かったなんて｡
I-I never knew...
That she had such low
tolerance for alcohol...
そういや これまで 一度も
飲ませたこと なかったわね｡
Come to think of it,
I've never let her drink before.
This is way beyond low tolerance.
いや 弱いってﾚﾍﾞﾙじゃないですよ｡
ｱﾙｺｰﾙから
未知なる力を抽出してますよ！
The alcohol is releasing some
kind of unknown power.
Okay, I'm gonna entertain
you good today.
よし！ 今日は たんまり
お前を楽しませてやるからよ｡
酒も入ったし… ﾋｯｸ｡
そろそろ座敷遊びでもするか？
We've had plenty to drink,
so let's play a game.
あっち向いてﾎｲ… ﾋｯｸ｡
い いや いいです｡
Look thataway.
N-No, it's okay.
ﾎﾞｸは太夫の隣で飲めるだけで
幸せですから ﾌﾌﾊﾊﾊ｡
I'm happy just to drink by your side.
知ってるだろ負けたほうが罰で
１枚１枚脱いでくやつ｡
Don't you know this game?
The loser has to remove
an article of clothing.
いや いいですってば！
太夫 ﾑﾘしなくていいです｡
No, it's okay.
You don't have to push yourself, Lady.
なんだ？ 私の裸が見たくねえのか
興味ｾﾞﾛか あん!?
What's that? You don't
wanna see me naked?
You have no interest?
いや そんなことないですよ｡
ただ 太夫今酔ってるから➡
No, that's not true.
But you're drunk right now,
あとで後悔しますよ｡
so you'll regret it later.
ﾌﾌ 見たいんだ｡ ｴﾛい 銀時ｴﾛい！
So you wanna see.
Perv.
Gintoki's a perv.
Such a pain! This lady is
such a pain in the ass!!
めんどくせえ！
太夫 ひどくめんどくせえ！
じゃあ私が負けたら
１枚１枚脱いでいくから➡
Then if I lose, I'll take something off,
so if you lose, you also
take something off...
お前負けたら１枚１枚脱げ｡
皮を｡
Like your skin.
Lady, look up the word "fair"
in the dictionary and circle it!
太夫 辞書で ﾌｪｱっていう字
調べて 赤線引いて！
それじゃあいくよ！
聞け～！
Here we go!
Listen!
ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝﾎﾟﾝ！
ｹﾞｯ｡
Rock, paper, scissors!
あっち向いてﾎｲ！
うわ～！ 太夫これもう➡
Look thataway!
Lady, this is already punishment enough!
すでに罰になってる～！
もういっちょ！
Again!
ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝﾎﾟﾝ！
よっしゃ～！
Rock, paper, scissors!
Okay!
あっち向いて ﾎ…｡
Look thataway!
ｷﾞｬ～！ 太夫
勝っても結局これｵﾚ負けてるぅ！
Lady, I still lose when I win!
ｼﾞｬﾝｹﾝ ｸﾞｰ！
ｱﾍﾞｼ！
Rock, paper, fist!
Look thataway and bam!
あっち向いて ﾄﾞｰﾝ！
うわっ！
(月詠)ｵﾗもういっちょ 立てｺﾗ！
One more time!
Stand up, damn it!
Rock, paper, scissors!
ﾌﾌ 月詠ったらﾎﾝﾄに楽しそう｡
Tsukuyo's having so much fun.
ああしてると
ﾎﾝﾄに ただの女の子みたいね｡
She looks like an ordinary girl now.
どこがぁ!?
How?!
ﾋｯｸ… よし次はｶﾙﾀでもやるか？
Okay, let's play cards next.
おい そこの隠れてるﾔﾂらも
こっちに来い｡
Hey, the people hiding over
there should join in.
３秒以内に来ないと殺すから｡
I'll kill you if you don't show yourselves
in three seconds.
(月詠)は～い １ ２…｡
Ready? One, two...
うぅ… う～ん｡
うぅ もう勘弁してください…｡
No more, please...
あぁ…｡
見回りか？
Going on patrol?
結局 変わりはしねえんだな
お前は｡
In the end, you never change.
なぁ もし…
もし この傷がなかったら➡
Say, if...
If I didn't have this scar...
わっちはもっと
別の生き方をしていたかのう｡
Could I have lived a different life?
変わりゃしねえだろ｡
You wouldn't be any different.
それが ﾃﾒｴが選んだ ﾃﾒｴらしい
生き方ってやつなんだろ｡
That's the path you've chosen,
your way of life.
後悔する必要はねえ｡
There's no need to regret it.
恥じる必要はねえ｡
There's no need to feel any shame.
誰でもねえ
ﾃﾒｴ自身で選んだ道だ｡
You, and nobody else, chose
this path yourself.
胸張って歩けばいい｡
Walk tall.
ﾃﾒｴのﾂﾗは 醜くなんかねえよ｡
Your face isn't ugly.
傷ひとつねえ魂持った ｷﾚｲなﾂﾗだ｡
It's a pretty face carrying a clean soul.
銀時…｡
Gintoki...
お前たちに会えてよかった｡
I'm glad to have met you all.
[Trailer]
[In response to calls from passionate fans,]
[we finally have]
[a movie!!]
[That sword-]
You... That sword...
I wasn't the one who cut him down.
is said to suck human blood.]
Right, Benizakura?
[GinTama the Movie: Benizakura Arc]
[Danger creeps toward Gintoki.]
Gin-san!
[Their name is-]
You think you can win against
Matako Kijima's quick-draw?!
[The Kiheitai]
I don't have a Lolita complex.
I'm a feminist.
What's with this girl?!
[Go quick.]
Elizabeth!
[Shinsuke Takasugi returns]
Don't ever call them my chums again.
There are no warm feelings
between us anymore.
When did our paths diverge?
[Their beginnings were the same...]
We may have started
from the same place.
But we've been looking to
different things ever since.
ｷｻﾏ その刀！
[Original Story: Hideaki
Sorachi (Weekly JUMP)]
ﾔﾂを斬ったのは ｵﾚじゃない｡
なぁ… 紅桜よ｡
[He's the dumbest samurai
in the universe, bastard.]
The intense fight is bringing back the fighting
skills his body still remembers!
[The excitement returns to the big screen!]
銀さん！
So that is Gintoki Sakata
and Kotaro Katsura.
この 来島また子の早撃ちに
勝てると思ってんすか！
They are strong...
I'd like to face off with them some time.
ﾛﾘｺﾝじゃない ﾌｪﾐﾆｽﾄです｡
Takasugi!
We'll do everything to take you out!
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ先輩！
[GinTama the Movie: The New Benizakura Arc
New Translation
Nationwide - Golden Week 2010]
[Note: Golden Week falls under the first week of May]
Uh, what is this?
二度と ｵﾚたちを
同志なんて呼び方するんじゃねえ｡
What? A trailer for GinTama the Movie.
そんな 甘っちょろいもんじゃ
ねえんだよ ｵﾚたちは｡
GinTama can finally join the
other popular Jump anime.
いつから違った ｵﾚたちの道は｡
Uh, no!
This is that fake movie preview
we used last time!
ﾌｯ… たしかに ｵﾚたちは➡
So after the fake ending scam, we're
going to have a fake movie scam?!
始まりこそ
同じ場所だったかもしれねえ｡
Well, the decision came so suddenly
that there wasn't any time,
だが あの頃から ｵﾚたちは
同じ場所など見ちゃいめえ｡
and then we were like,
we can just use this.
You're still making excuses?!
Might as well skip the effort and reuse
footage for the movie itself.
Toss in a few new scenes
and you'll fool them all.
That won't work!
Really?
Most of Sunrise's movies
are recompilations.
あれは
極限の命のやりとりのなかで➡
Like XXXX and XXXX and XXXX.
体の奥に眠る
戦いの記憶が甦ったのか!?
Those are all Gundam series!
Oops, he said it.
And there you have it.
GinTama the Movie:
The New Benizakura Arc.
Come shake my hand in the theater!
あれが 坂田銀時と桂小太郎…｡
Who's gonna believe that?!
[And so, we have a movie coming up.
Sorry that it isn't a Hollywood production.]
強い… 一手
死合うてもらいたいものだな｡
[Adding "New Translation" will make it work.
That's what a certain someone said.]
高杉～っ！
全力で ﾃﾒｴを ぶった斬る！
[See you next time.]
ちょ… これ なんですか？
なんですか って
『劇場版 銀魂』の予告編だよ｡
(神楽)これでやっと 『銀魂』も
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ人気ｱﾆﾒの仲間入りね！
って 違うだろ！
これ 前にやった➡
ﾆｾ映画予告編の
使いまわしじゃないっすか！
終わる終わる詐欺の次は
映画やるやる詐欺ですか!?
いや～ 急に決まっちゃってさ｡
予告作るひま ねえな｡
と思ってたら いいのあったじゃん
ってね｡
まだ言うか！
めんどくさいから
本編のほうも使いまわしでいいね｡
新作ｶｯﾄの一つ二つ入れとけば
ﾔﾂら全員 騙せるｱﾙ｡
んなわけねえだろ！
そうか？
ｻﾝﾗｲｽﾞの作る映画なんて
ほとんど 再編集ものだぞ｡
…とか …とか …とか｡
ｶﾞﾝﾀﾞﾑばっかじゃねえか！
あ～あ 言っちゃったｱﾙ…｡
それじゃあ
『劇場版 銀魂 新訳 紅桜編』｡
映画館で ﾎﾞｸと握手ｱﾙ！
って そんなの信用できるか！